(Wind howls)
- Can you make out the beacon light?
- Not yet!
- About time we came up with it.
- Look to starboard!
Where?
I've lost it. It's gone. Did you see it?
No.
Nothing there!
(Crash)
Argh!
Tell 'em to make sure
no-one gets clear of the wreck!
No-one, d'you hear?
(Man shouts orders)
That's all! Load up the horses!
Carry the rest yourselves!
Come on!
(Man barks orders)
Get the stuff up to the inn!
Come on!
Come along now!
You're sure no-one got away?
You can reckon on that, Joss.
Aye, you can reckon on that.
Joss!
Help!
I told you to make certain, you fool!
Can't you use your eyes?
Do you want the lot of us to swing?
(Agonised scream)
(Whistling)
I don't like it. I don't like it at all.
- That place gives me the creeps.
- Eh?
That place. Jamaica Inn. It's got a bad name.
It's not healthy, that's why.
There's queer things goes on there.
Queer things. I won't stop there,
not if she were to offer me double fare.
Is Jamaica Inn on this road?
Yes.
How much further is Jamaica Inn?
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Gee up!
Why are we going so fast?
What's happened? Have the horses bolted?
BOTH: It's Jamaica Inn.
But this is where I want to get out.
Hi, coachman! Why don't you stop?
I want to get out!
Coachman, listen to me, you fool!
Pull up at once!
Why don't you stop, you fool?
Stop, I tell you!
Whoa!
Why didn't you stop? Are you deaf?
I've been shouting myself silly.
You've taken me past Jamaica Inn.
Take me back at once.
You'd better try Squire Pengallan's instead.
They say he's partial to young women.
Here's your box. Gee up!
MAN: I think we owe a toast to Sir Humphrey.
Sir Humphrey.
Eh? What?
Jove, yes.
Pengallan.
Thank you.
Might have asked you to drink the health of
His brand-new Majesty George IV, but I forgot.
Fact is, I haven't been on speaking terms
for years with the fat fool.
You were much in his company at
one time, Sir Humphrey.
When Charlie Fox and Sheridan would
be there with him in the Pavilion at Brighton.
In those days he was still a gentleman.
Now he's nothing but a painted bag
of maraschino and plum pudding.
WOMAN:
Last summer we made a tour of the lakes.
Which lake do you admire the most,
Sir Humphrey?
Chadwick!
Which lake did I admire the most?
- Windermere, sir.
- Windermere.
It is very beautiful.
Why not a toast to beauty, Sir Humphrey?
Why not?
Chadwick, my figurine.
I need inspiration, by gad.
- Oh, there's beauty.
- But it's not alive.
It's more alive than half the people here.
Look at them, what?
You want to see beauty alive? Chadwick!
Ask Sam how long Nancy's going to be.
- Nancy?
- The most beautiful creature west of Exeter.
That's why he stays here
and never comes to London any more.
He keeps a girl here, the monster.
- Then I prefer not to make her acquaintance.
- No. I'm curious.
Yes, by Jove.
Have her in, Pengallan.
Here she is.
My exquisite Nancy.
(Horse whinnies)
(Murmurs of surprise)
Brought me in a hundred guineas yesterday.
Ran away with the Bodmin Steeplechase,
didn't you, my dear? Chadwick, what's that?
It's a woman, sir.
Don't argue with your women
when I'm entertaining.
WOMAN: The coachman left me stranded.
Ask your master to lend me a horse and trap.
Let's have a look at her.
Ringwood, bet you 20-1 in guineas she's ugly.
I'll take you.
Would you er...
oblige me by taking off that coat for a moment?
Why should I?
I have a wager here.
Always respect a wager.
Would you allow me?
But you're an exquisite shape, too.
My dear,
you're a beauty.
Ringwood!
You've won.
Here y'are!
RINGWOOD:
Look, here. I say, my bet, you know.
"She walks in beauty like the night.
Of cloudless climes and starry skies, hmm?
And all that's best of dark and bright
Meet in her aspect...
...and her eyes."
Thank you, sir, but I didn't come for poetry,
but for a horse.
A horse?
Being worthy of Lord Byron's poetry,
you shall have the horse.
My name is Sir Humphrey Pengallan.
I'm squire of Pengallan and justice of the peace.
I'm Mary Yellan from Ireland.
- And you're going where?
- To Jamaica Inn.
To Jamaica Inn?
You can't go there.
- Why not?
- Sam!
This young lady wants to know
why she can't go to Jamaica Inn. Tell her.
Ooh, very rough there, miss.
No place for a young lady.
See, even Sam knows that.
No, you better stay here.
No, of course not.
I've come all the way from Ireland alone,
because I've nobody there now.
Your parents?
I'm going to Jamaica Inn,
because my Aunt Patience is there.
What a lovely horse.
Yes. Could you ride her?
Yes, of course.
I've been riding since I was a child.
Well, you shall ride her to the inn.
Thank you,
but I've got a box outside.
Oh, um... l'll take the box
and conduct you myself to er... your relative.
Sam, saddle the bay as well.
Chadwick!
Chadwick, this is Miss Mary Yellan
who's going to Jamaica Inn.
So she said, sir. I don't understand.
You've never understood anything,
so why be surprised at yourself now?
Try to understand this.
Miss Yellan is my friend.
If she returns here at any time, admit her at
once. See that she has everything she requires.
Give me my greatcoat and muffler.
And a thick scarf for this lady.
Pardon me.
Chadwick,
I'll have some hot brandy when I come back
and see that they put a warming pan in the bed.
Very good, Sir Humphrey.
If you'll wait a moment, miss, I'll get the scarf.
But I really don't need it.
If I can be of any service, please command me.
Remember, I'm Pengallan,
and this is Pengallan land.
- Don't forget, now.
- No, I won't.
Good night, Miss er... Yellan.
Good night, Sir Humphrey.
(Woman sobbing)
(Men laughing)
Who's there?
What do you want?
Does Mrs Patience Merlyn live here?
She might.
And she might not.
Depending on your business.
I'm her niece from Ireland.
You must have heard.
I'm coming to live with my aunt and uncle.
What?
What put that in your head?
Who told you so, eh?
That's my business.
Go and tell your master I'm here.
Aren't you going to give me a kiss first?
You'll... You'll suffer for this when my uncle's
told of it. I'll have you turned out of here.
- You'll see.
- Oh, you wouldn't be hard on us, ma'am.
- You see, your aunt would miss me.
- Get out of my way!
Correct.
Entirely correct.
I'm your aunt's loving husband,
your great big uncle Joss.
Come on.
WOMAN: Who's there?
There we are.
Aunt Patience.
Mary. Mary, my sister's Mary.
- You know me, then, Aunt Patience?
- Yes, my dear, yes.
You're so like your mother.
When I heard your voice at first,
I thought it was hers.
And then when I saw you,
I thought for the moment...
She said you were expecting her to stay.
No, Joss, no.
But I wrote to you telling you everything.
Nothing came.
You wrote...
Mary,
you're in black.
Yes.
Mother died three weeks ago today.
(Mumbles) I'll have a drink.
How did it happen?
She hadn't been well,
but she said she must leave her bed and work.
You know how Mother was.
(Whistling)
Patience. Don't stand there yappering, woman.
Get the girl's box inside.
Yes. Yes, Joss.
No, no, Aunt Patience, let me.
Easy, easy.
Your new uncle's very particular.
He's not the sort to let lovely ladies
spoil themselves with rough work.
He knows different, does Joss.
Lively with it, Patience, my dear.
- I'll take this end.
- No. I can manage. It isn't heavy, Mary.
- You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
- Mary, don't say anything.
I've had pretty women
pay me compliments before.
Stand clear there.
There.
Our Mary's a little bit sour tonight,
but, bless you, the best of us
can't be sweet-tempered on an empty belly.
Fill it up for her.
Yes, I'll get her something to eat.
Mary, if you'll come with me.
I won't be a minute.
If you'll sit down and rest.
- I'll set the table.
- No, no, no, no.
You'll be tired after your long journey.
I'm not. Where's the cloth and supper things?
Over there in the middle drawer.
(Raucous laughter)
It's nothing. Only some late customers
in the parlour. They'll be going soon, no doubt.
(Raucous laughter)
Shut that gab!
Keep it quiet.
- You see, boys, we've got a visitor.
- Harry told us.
She's a neat piece from what I've seen of her.
Very neat.
That's all you think of, women.
Vanities of the flesh.
Following petticoats
along the path to everlasting corruption.
- Salvation's off again.
- You can laugh now.
But you'll sing a different tune,
when you're roasting in the consuming fire
that's waiting for all of us.
Me included.
- Where are you going, Harry?
- To pay my respects.
She's not partial to your sort, Harry.
What about me in my new lace cuffs?
Anything in mind that way yourself?
Well, I hadn't given the matter a thought,
but I might.
I said I might, Harry.
All right, Joss.
Added to which,
she's my wife's niece from Ireland.
Why didn't you say that before?
My business, Harry, my business.
I knew a girl once.
Come from Ireland.
Talked funny, she did. Like a foreigner.
But it was all right.
I'm not what you expected, am I?
I was only a child when you went away,
Aunt Patience.
I can only just remember you then.
And what was I like then?
You were beautiful.
Was I?
Yes...
I suppose I was.
No doubt your mother told you all about me.
You're thinking I'm paid out for leaving home.
For running away. Well, you're wrong.
Joss has been a good husband to me.
There's nothing I'd change even if I could.
It's hard work and it's risky work.
It's work we'll rot in chains for one day.
All in a neat row.
And what do we get out of it? Next to nothing.
Why, a man's share doesn't come to enough
to hold body and soul together.
That last wreck didn't bring in
what it should have. That's what I say.
That's what you say.
No, that's what Sydney said.
- So, you've been yapping, eh?
- No, no, Mr Merlyn, I assure you.
Showing off your arithmetic, eh?
Doing pretty sums for poor lads
that can't read nor reckon.
You're out to list the goods,
not set a price on them.
Just a minute, Joss.
I told him the last haul didn't fetch
a quarter of what it should have done.
You did, eh?
Reckoning by our share of it,
maybe you're not getting
the right price for the stuff.
Maybe there's a leak somewhere.
(Harry whistles)
You're looking thoughtful, Harry.
Perhaps you'll give us
the benefit of your sentiments.
If any.
About this leak, I think the word is,
if you've a notion in your mind, Harry,
don't be bashful.
Spit it out. We'd be glad to listen.
I wouldn't know about that, Joss.
Well, perhaps I would.
Supposing there is a leak.
And supposing it happens before the goods
get to the inn, do you follow me?
Some absent-minded chap
might mislay a piece or two,
in a manner of speaking,
on the way up from the wreck.
Have you ever thought of that?
How long have you been with me?
A matter of five years, Joss.
Salvation?
We've been lost souls together
for two years and seven months, Joss.
Sydney?
Almost two and a half years, Mr Merlyn.
Dandy?
Let's see, now. I was carrying on
with a bit in Penzance around that time.
Here she is. Annie.
That makes it four years, Joss.
And you?
I'll tell them for you.
Mr Trehearne has been with us
the enormous time of two months.
Eight weeks.
56 days.
How's that for arithmetic?
What do you say to that, Mr Trehearne?
PATIENCE: Joss.
JOSS: Clear out!
Joss, please.
Why, what's wrong?
Joss, Mary's just told me,
she came to the inn with Squire Pengallan.
He asked her why she was coming here
and about us.
And, seeing he's a magistrate, I thought...
Joss, you don't think he's found out anything?
What's this about Sir Humphrey, eh?
How did you come to meet him?
Why, I called on him.
The coach took me a long way past here.
So I went to the house for help.
Sir Humphrey was very kind and most obliging.
He knows how to behave towards a woman.
He even lent me a horse to ride here.
One that won him a hundred guineas
in the county steeplechase.
We didn't get the haul we hoped for tonight, sir.
There was a full gale blowing down there
and the ship broke clean in two, sir.
Get a pair of scissors, Merlyn.
Yes, sir.
Why did you leave this blood on?
What do you think we're conducting?
A slaughterhouse? Cut it off.
There were so many tumbling in.
It was butcher's work.
What have they to live for, poor scum?
You were right to put them out of their misery.
Look at this exquisite stuff. Worth the miserable
lives of a hundred rum-rotten sailors.
Perfection of its own kind.
That's all that matters, Merlyn.
Whatever is perfect of its kind.
I'd transport all the riffraff in Bristol
to Botany Bay
to save one beautiful woman a single headache.
Something you don't understand. Never will.
Because you're neither
a philosopher nor a gentleman.
- But you made certain, no survivors?
- Certain sure, sir.
I'm sorry about that girl Mary, sir.
We didn't know she was coming.
She'll be no harm.
I'll get her away in the morning.
Make up the fire. It's cold.
- Get me a drink.
- Yes, sir.
I didn't expect you so soon, sir,
before I'd put the light in the window.
A man's a fool to stir out on a night like this.
Taking a bit of a risk, wasn't it,
coming before I got the men out of the way?
Everything's a risk.
This girl, Mary, not without character.
A mind of her own.
Oh, you leave her to me, sir.
I'll manage her, just as I manage my Patience.
- Have you looked at the stuff?
- I don't see any resemblance to your wife.
Maybe not, but my Patience was
a bit of a beauty when I married her. Why, I...
This won't do, Merlyn. It's not enough.
No, sir, it's not quite what we looked for.
Better luck next time, eh, Sir Humphrey?
We could do with it.
The men are getting impatient.
I can deal with them, but they're asking
where the money goes. They want more.
What for? Rot their innards out sooner
with the blue ruin you sell 'em?
Listen, Merlyn. I want more.
I know what to do with money when I have it.
That's why I must have it.
- Do you understand? I must have it.
- Yes, sir.
Anything more this week
while the weather still holds?
Perhaps tomorrow.
I've been thinking about your wife's niece.
It seems a pity to bundle her off
before she's seen anything of the county.
I've nothing against her stopping.
Provided, of course, she's kept out of the way.
(Commotion downstairs)
Up to your rooms, both of you.
Patience, take her supper upstairs.
Now, try and sleep, dear. You must be tired.
Good night.
- Look at that.
- Ooh, how much?
You was right, Joss. See that?
Best part of fifteen pound in gold.
What did I tell you?
JOSS: You've got yourself
in a pretty mess, Mr Trehearne.
What have you got to say?
Get me a drink.
Choking gives you a thirst.
Thomas, I'm sure you'll oblige the gentleman.
Seems I'm a good guesser, Mr Trehearne.
How did you get it?
Saved.
You mean, you've been selling stuff on the side.
I'm ashamed of you, Mr Trehearne.
That's what I am.
Taking the bread out of the mouths of your pals.
There's your leak.
Not true.
He's making fools of the lot of you.
Where do you think the stuff goes?
Who gets rid of it?
Do you think Joss is in this by himself?
Well, go on, ask him! Ask him who!
DANDY: That was a cosh. Clean out.
The dirty thief.
- He asked for it all right.
- He done us. We do him.
What are we all waiting for?
(Harry whistles)
Try the other room.
See if you can find me a nice beam.
About six foot two off the floor.
Go on.
(Footsteps below)
JOSS:
Hold on. I'll see if the women are out of the way.
Don't want a lot of squawking.
Hurry up.
It's a new chap, Trehearne.
They found this gold on him.
Know anything about him?
He came from St lves a couple of months ago,
recommended by a pal.
- Can't just kick him out. That's obvious.
- He might talk.
- The men want to string him up tonight.
- Really? That's a trifle formal, isn't it?
Pistol. Oh, no. Too noisy.
Of course, you wouldn't want
to alarm your wife's niece.
I suppose it's as good a way as any.
No need for you to go. Tell 'em.
I haven't finished talking to you.
- Harry?
- Yes?
Get on with it.
- I'll be down in a minute.
- All right.
Come on, Salvation. Look sharp.
Stand back, the rest of you!
We don't want any gawpers here.
This is private, see. If you want a public hanging,
Syd, you won't have to wait long.
And you'll get a fine view of it
from the best position. Inside the rope.
(Laughter)
You're not old enough yet.
SALVATION: What about Joss?
HARRY: He says to get it over.
DANDY: Is this the place, Harry?
HARRY: That's it. Plenty of clearance.
Anything worth doing, I say,
is worth doing proper.
(Harry whistles)
Come on.
Let's make a quick job of it
before he comes round.
I won't be a party to that, Thomas.
It's only being kind to him.
He won't know nothing about it.
It's no kindness to send a man
into the next world unawares.
It's heathen. That's what it is, I say.
Bring him round with a nip of spirits
and give him a fair chance to meditate.
I don't like the thought of it somehow.
It's like doing it in cold blood.
Come on. He's heavy.
- What do you say, Harry?
- I say shut your misbegotten mouths.
Both of you.
Aha!
At it again, Dandy?
Grab, grab, grab all the time.
We'll spin a coin for them buckles,
when I say the word.
Let's have a light.
(Harry whistles)
HARRY: All together.
Pull!
- Don't you let him have them, Harry!
- Go on.
- Throttle him, Dandy.
- Go on, Harry.
HARRY: Shut your mouth.
Do you want to bring Joss down?
You've got to get out of here.
They'll be back in a minute.
Please, you must try.
Quick, quick.
- You mustn't stop here. Get away.
- I couldn't leave Aunt Patience.
Please, you must hurry.
(Horse gallops away)
Quick. Before Joss...
There you are, my dear.
Been saying good night to Patience?
Yes, I've been thinking things over.
"She's a sweet, pretty girl," I said to myself,
"with a lot of character."
It seems a pity to send her away,
before she's hardly seen anything of the county.
"She can stay here," I said,
"just as long as she feels inclined."
HARRY: Joss! Joss!
Come down, Joss!
(Shouting from downstairs)
He's been took, Joss.
- What? Who?
- Trehearne, he's been took by the angels.
- Of course, he's been took. I know that.
- But alive, Joss. Alive.
Mary.
It was you.
You set that man free.
Listen to me. You must leave Jamaica Inn now,
this minute, do you hear?
There y'are.
That blasted girl, I'll kill her!
For pity's sake, go now.
Before Joss comes up.
Where's that girl?
Where is she?
You let her go.
JOSS:
Thomas, take this lamp. Look in the stables.
Harry, give me a hand.
We'll go through the yard.
If some of you don't get a move on,
I'll break your blasted necks!
SALVATION: They can't have got away so soon.
- We can't stay here. Come on.
- Where?
Down by the harbour. I know a place.
We'll be safe there for a while.
Come on. Hurry.
SYDNEY: Joss! Shall I search the moor?
HARRY: Try the yard.
We'll have to get 'em,
if we stay out all night.
There's not a sign of either of them.
- They've got clear. Any luck?
- No.
If we don't find 'em,
we'll swing for it, like as not.
Harry, take a couple of men down to the coast.
Thomas, get your brother and any of our chaps
you can find. Search the moors.
- What are you going to do, Joss?
- I'll take the Bodmin turnpike.
SIR HUMPHREY: Chadwick!
- It's very late, sir.
- She was a very charming girl, Chadwick.
I didn't mention it before, sir, but the butcher
was here while you were at dinner.
- He wants his account settled.
- Remarkably unattractive occupation.
Drearily dismembering carcass after carcass.
- I suppose they must live, sir.
- Must they?
There's nearly £40 owing to the butcher,
£35 to the baker.
You see, sir, butcher, baker...
Don't butcher and baker me!
You old numbskull!
I'm sorry, huh, Chadwick, what?
Doing your duty.
That's all, Master Humphrey.
These outbursts of mine are quite inexcusable.
I can't think what comes over me.
By the way, Chadwick,
what happened to my grandfather?
Yes, went mad, didn't he?
(Knock on window)
No need for you to hang about, Chadwick.
Go to bed.
How dare you come here to me.
Haven't I told you a score of times?
Yes, but Trehearne has got away.
That girl set him free.
I couldn't help it. It was while I was with you.
- What have you done with her?
- She's gone, too.
Oh, a general exodus, apparently.
You persuaded your wife to remain, I hope.
The men are out looking for them now.
We're doing our best.
Is that all you came here to say?
That chap Trehearne knows too much.
If he was to inform against me and the others...
You're losing your head, Merlyn.
Even if Trehearne lives to do any informing,
he'll do it here.
I'm the only justice in the neighbourhood.
If you can't keep your wits about you,
kindly allow me to keep mine.
If I didn't, you'd never see another wreck.
When the brains are out,
the body dies, Merlyn.
And I needn't remind you
that in this little organisation,
you and your fellows are only the carcass.
- The brains are here, what?
- I'm sorry. I was only trying to warn you.
Will you let me do the warning?
If you want any more fat pickings on the shore,
just obey orders.
And don't come here again. Get out! Get out!
(Seagulls cry)
Hey! What?
Come back. What on earth?
- Now, what do you think you're doing?
- Let go!
Don't be a fool. You can't even row.
Leave me alone!
You're not afraid of me?
You are. Well, that's women for you.
Save your life one minute
and frightened for their own the next.
Yes, I'm not a very pretty sight at the moment,
but I don't bite.
You think I don't know why my aunt is frightened
for her life, that I don't know what you
- and the rest of you are doing at Jamaica Inn?
- No. What?
Thieves, smugglers, cut-throats, for all I know,
and I'm not staying!
Look!
Harry, here!
A very significant piece of flotsam, eh?
BOY: It came out of the cave.
Suppose you ask your brother
to take you for a nice row? Follow me?
- Rather!
- Can I go, too, Harry? I saw it first.
No, you cut back
and tell Joss everything's lovely. Run!
Dandy, you go and get some rope.
This way.
(Harry whistles)
You know what you've done? The tide's going
out now, but it'll be high water again before dark.
We can't stay here without that boat.
We'll have to run for it
as soon as the tide's low enough.
Trust me to land myself with a woman.
- On the other hand, you did save my life.
- I hope you'll make better use of it in the future.
- A tall order for a desperate character like me.
- No doubt.
A smuggler and a cut-throat, I think you said.
Do you think there's any hope for me?
- Tell me, what ought I to do?
- Anything you please.
I used to be a sailor. I could go back to sea.
- I'm not in the least interested.
- You must be.
- You're responsible for me.
- I am not.
But for you, I shouldn't be here at all.
You can't deny that.
When we're safe in Truro,
I shall put myself in your hands.
- Oh, please be quiet.
- Oh, cheer up. We'll be there by...
(Whistling)
SALVATION: Take the little book.
There's a beautiful hymn on page 1 3.
"While at death's door I trembling stand."
Very comforting.
- Makes dying a pleasure, so he says.
- A handsome couple.
Breaks my heart to disturb 'em.
Coming down!
HARRY: Will you send the lady up first
or do you fancy it yourself?
DANDY: Ladies first, I always say.
- What can we do?
- They know we're stuck.
They must have seen the boat drift out.
HARRY: Just in case you'd like a bit of help,
Mr Trehearne,
your old friend Thomas
is coming down to offer his arm.
He's out.
Any more? We're fond of company.
You'll get it all right. Never you fear.
It'll be a pleasure. Come on. Who's it to be?
Here, Belcher. Grab this.
Slip it round that bit of rock. Quick!
Do you hear that?
There's only one way out of this.
Can you swim?
Just to please you, Mr Trehearne, so you won't
feel lonely, we're all three coming down.
Please don't trouble with me. I'll be in the way.
It'll be hard enough for you getting away alone.
I'll be all right. Joss daren't harm me.
- Can you swim?
- A little.
- Take off that dress and your shoes.
- I can't do that.
- Take it off.
- I can't.
- All right, then. I will.
- No, you won't. I will.
(Harry whistles)
(Yawns) I shall be glad when this little job's over.
We've been up all night.
Yes, it'll be nice to get to bed.
DANDY: What about the girl?
Do we hand her over to Joss?
They're coming. Come on!
HARRY: Now, Mr Trehearne...
That's the spirit. You're doing fine.
That's funny.
First time I've ever seen a woman swimming.
All this... this salt.
Look! They've sent a boat. It's coming this way.
Quick! Those rocks.
Hold onto my shoulder. Are you all right?
- Hold on. The boat's coming.
- I can't.
(Jem whispers) Here it is.
- Keep it up. They're going.
- It's no good.
- I'm going.
- Hang on to me.
SIR HUMPHREY: Dowland.
Ah, good morning, Dowland.
I haven't had a taste
of that sloe gin of yours this year.
- I'm three pounds short, Squire Pengallan.
- I told you...
Dowland, I want money just as you do.
I can't be Squire Pengallan on nothing.
- Why are you short?
- That lad of mine.
- He went down with a bad leg and it won't heal.
- Take him to Dr Mackintosh.
Give the doctor my compliments.
Ask him to look at the leg. Pay £3 next time.
- Thank you, Squire.
- Give him a receipt, Davis.
- But I warned...
- The receipt, Davis.
This man's forefathers
were farming Pengallan land
when yours were hedge tinkers. Next.
- Where can we go? Which way?
- We'd best make for the turnpike.
Wait! What house is that over there?
- The Squire's.
- You mean Sir Humphrey?
I know him. I was there last night.
He'll be glad to help us. Come on.
This is the fellow I mentioned, Sir Humphrey.
Burdkin. A rank radical.
DAVIS: Burdkin.
Er, well, Burdkin?
I've come to complain. I want my rights.
Your rights? I don't listen to that sort of talk.
- I've the law on my side.
- You haven't.
I'm the law here and on your side I won't be
while you take that tone.
Next you'll be telling me you're as good as I am.
I'm a man, same as you.
Put that out of your head
before it lands you in the hulks.
You're not as good as I am and never will be.
Nature was against it from the start.
Everything else has been against it since.
I'm a gentleman.
Why, you great...
Have him run out, Davis.
Er, don't give him 24 hours.
If you please, Squire Pengallan.
Why if it isn't Granny Tremarney.
Yes, Your Honour.
It's my roof. I've complained to Mr Davis about it,
but he takes no notice. It leaks all the time now.
- Give her a new roof, Davis.
- But, Sir Humphrey...
I said a new roof.
She's my oldest tenant, hm?
While I'm here, she'll be snug.
I'm the only man under the rank of marquis
who ever gambled ten years at White's Club
and kept his estate
out of the hands of the moneylenders.
While I have a roof, she shall have one.
MARY: I must see Sir Humphrey...
- What's this?
MARY:you're to let me in. It's very important.
My dear child, what on earth's happened?
You're... soaked to the skin.
Chadwick, get Mrs Black and close the door.
Come to the fire.
Tell them to go now, Davis. Some other time.
But you're positively blue with cold.
- Where have you been?
- Swimming.
- For our lives.
- Er... Who, er... Who is this?
This is Jem Trehearne.
We got away from Jamaica Inn last night.
It's a horrible place. It's nothing better than
a den of smugglers. They'd have murdered him.
- She saved my life, sir.
- Well, this is extraordinary.
We need your help. My aunt's still there.
If you only knew...
You must tell me the whole story,
but, first, we must find you some dry things.
Oh, Mrs Black, take this young lady upstairs
and see if you can find her something to wear.
Will you come this way, miss?
- Could I speak to you for a moment, please?
- Of course.
SIR HUMPHREY: Really?
(lndistinct voices)
Well, er... We, er...
We must see what we can do, hm?
- Thank you. You're very kind.
- Not at all.
(Door closes)
Oh, er, excuse me, sir.
Chadwick!
Get the erm... fellow some er... bread and beer.
I'll deal with you later.
MAN: So, I let her have it with nine
eight-pounders, then we went alongside...
"Wherein I spake of most disastrous chances,
of moving accidents by flood and field
of hairbreadth 'scapes..."
- Captain Murray, you'll stay to dinner?
- You keep the best table in Cornwall.
- I should hope so. Why go?
- I'm due to rejoin my ship at Falmouth.
By the time you've finished your port
and walnuts, I shall be sailing past the house.
- The deuce you will.
(Door opens)
I must have a word with you.
- Well?
- Er, in private.
There's nothing you can tell me
these gentlemen shouldn't know.
One of a gang of smugglers
from Jamaica Inn.
Smugglers, eh?
Have you got any good brandies through?
Well, yes, as a matter of fact,
- I've got a list of them here.
- Kindly remember I'm a justice of the peace.
Nevertheless, I think you'll be rather interested
in these brandies.
Erm...
Er, gentlemen,
I think I must look into this matter in private.
- What?
- (Chuckles)
Come along, my dear chap.
Pengallan, if you don't find something good
for me, I'll report you to the Commission.
After you, my dear fellow.
I've placed some bread and beer for this person
in the harness room.
Have you now? Place some cold chicken
and claret "for this person" in the study.
Find some clothes for Mr Trehearne.
Mine would be a trifle generous. One of
Lord George's would be nearer the mark.
- For this gentleman?
- Yes. Will you hurry? Hurry!
- Master Humphrey...
- I must apologise.
I hadn't the least idea who you were. Now, a stiff
glass of brandy till you're fed and in dry clothes.
I'm most awfully obliged to you.
Not at all. Come in.
I hold the rank of Lieutenant
in His Majesty's Royal Navy.
I was seconded for duty from the Home Office.
I've been at some pains to conceal my identity.
I still haven't the least notion what it's all about,
but swallow this before you tell me.
I always had a great admiration for the service.
I knew Collingwood well.
All fine fellows. A trifle desiccated, perhaps.
One can't have everything.
Now, what is all this business?
Smuggling?
No, it's much worse than that, sir. Wrecking.
Deliberate, organised wrecking.
- Not here, though?
- Yes, sir. Along this coast.
Always had wrecks here, you know.
A very dangerous coast.
Lloyds discovered that these wrecks
had one curious feature in common.
Indeed? Drink that up.
I think I'll join you with the brandy.
It has been er... quite an eventful morning.
What had these wrecks in common?
There were never any survivors.
Er, Mr Trehearne,
if what you tell me is true,
it's the most dreadful thing I've ever heard.
- We hear of wrecks down here...
- Lloyds consulted with the Home Office.
They became convinced these wreckers
had accurate information
- of the movements and cargoes of ships...
(Knock at door)
Captain Murray
wishes to say goodbye to you, sir.
- Would you excuse me?
- Certainly.
I'm just going. I enjoyed myself immensely.
You're a prince.
- Goodbye, Captain. Bon voyage.
- I'm coming back again.
I shall be thinking of you out there in this wind
when I'm sitting over my port tonight.
- All right?
- Jolly good.
Well, er, Mr Trehearne,
kindly continue.
My researches took me to Jamaica Inn.
The landlord is the ringleader.
That wreck last night was carried out by his men.
- You were actually there?
- No, thank heaven, I was still on probation.
But I helped carry the goods up afterwards.
Have you erm...
Have you reported all this to your superiors?
No, not yet.
I'm after bigger fry than Joss Merlyn.
I don't follow you. Erm...
You er... said he was the ringleader.
At Jamaica Inn, yes,
but he gets his orders from outside.
His information comes from outside.
His thinking's done for him outside.
- By whom?
- I don't know.
Merlyn's own wife doesn't know. The gang don't
even know. That's the man we've got to find.
(Wind howls)
Yes, Joss has called the men for tonight.
There's to be another wreck.
They won't know where
until they get information from their leader.
In order to give them that information,
he'll be going to the inn tonight.
- We must get there first.
- We can't do that single-handed.
I'll ride for help to the nearest garrison.
But that'll take time. We mustn't let this fellow
slip through our fingers.
You and I will go to the inn. My groom can take
a message to the garrison at Truro for you.
Take some of those.
You say Merlyn's riffraff won't be there till later?
I fancy we two can hold the fort
till the military come.
- I'm game, if you are, sir.
- Excellent. This is positively exciting.
(Knock at door)
- Come in.
- Chadwick, your money or your life?
- The clothes, sir. I've not told Lord George.
Who's the commander at Truro?
Er...
Captain... Boyle, an Irishman, I believe.
Good fellow in a pinch.
I'll write him a note.
No, I'll do that.
You get into Lord George's breeches.
To, er...
Captain... Boyle... erm...
officer commanding...
...county militia,
Truro.
What shall I erm... say to him?
You know this style of thing.
Your help is needed urgently.
Your er... help?
Help, yes. Help.
Is... needed... urgently.
(Jem continues dictating)...which...
SIR HUMPHREY: For which...?
For which, er...? For which, er...
JEM:to give your immediate attention...
JEM: I have with me an officer of the law,
James Trehearne...
SIR HUMPHREY: Officer of the law,
James Trehearne.
JEM: Got that? All right, Sir Humphrey?
SIR HUMPHREY: Yes.
He reports that the wreckers have their
headquarters at Jamaica Inn, Pengallan.
And has enough evidence
to hang the landlord and his accomplices.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
A miraculous fit.
You put Lord George in the shade, what?
I'd better get you a hat.
Chadwick!
- We must leave at once, you know.
- One moment, sir.
The girl, Miss Yellan,
she mustn't know about this.
Oh, no, no, no. That must wait.
Poor thing. Evidently devoted to her relative.
I had no choice, Sir Humphrey.
I couldn't tell her the truth.
Tell Sam I want him at once. Where is he?
- In the kitchen, sir.
- Sam!
You'd better have a warm cloak.
Get Mr Trehearne the blue cloak,
not the one with the astrakhan collar,
get him a hat, and get me my cloak and hat.
- Oh, Sam.
- Ride into Truro as fast as you can.
Deliver that to Captain Boyle
at Militia Headquarters.
SIR HUMPHREY: Gallop all the way.
SAM: Very good, sir.
Would you be good enough to tell Robbins
I want my coach at once? Come along.
Chadwick!
- Your coat, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
Would you tell Mrs Black
to look after the young lady
and if she can persuade her
to get a little sleep, so much the better?
Will you make my excuses for me?
Tell Lord George I'll be back for dinner.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, thank you so much.
Robbins!
Where is my coach?
Isn't it ready?
The young lady came round the back
and took it, sir.
BOTH: What?
- She said you had ordered it for her, sir.
- Do you think?
- Horses! Quick, will you?
You must come away with me while there's time.
That man I cut down was a law officer.
He's on his way here now with Sir Humphrey.
They've sent to Truro for help.
I must change.
Get your things together before they come.
I must tell Joss.
- No time.
- I'll not leave without Joss.
They know the truth and, Aunt Patience, so do I.
This is your last chance to be free of him.
No.
He's a wrecker, a murderer.
But he's my husband. Oh, Mary,
you don't understand. You don't know him.
(Footsteps)
She's come here to warn us. We must get away.
Where's that fellow? Where's Trehearne?
Joss, they're coming for you.
Trehearne's a law officer. We can't...
(Knock at door)
(Knocking continues)
Keep quiet.
I don't think I need tell you
why I'm here with this officer, Merlyn.
I fancy you'll be able to guess.
I demand the right to search your premises.
Perhaps you'd show us round, Mr Merlyn?
All clear in there, Sir Humphrey.
So, you're here.
How quick of you, Mr Trehearne,
but law officers waste very little time.
I'm sorry. Come here, Mrs Merlyn.
- She had nothing to do with this.
- I hope not.
Why didn't you tell me who you were?
So you could have warned your aunt?
And why not? She's innocent. She won't run
away. Nothing will drive her away from Joss.
If that is the case, perhaps Mrs Merlyn
will mix us something to drive out the cold.
What would you like?
A hot brandy, if you'd be so kind.
JEM: Up the stairs, Joss. Go on! Get up.
- Joss?
I'm sorry about this, believe me.
But try not to worry. We'll do our best.
Aunt Patience,
you've known about Joss all along.
I love him. People can't help
being what they are. Joss can't. I can't.
- There's nothing to be done.
- Even now you could leave him.
Go and put the kettle on the fire
while I get the brandy.
This is where he comes in, up these stone steps.
You're expecting a visitor, aren't you?
He comes to one of these rooms.
I've tried that door, but it's locked.
Give me the key.
- I'll break that door down.
- Don't be a fool. Give him the key.
Go on. Get in.
Mind your head, Sir Humphrey.
These doors are rather low.
Oh, er, thank you.
- This looks more like it.
- Never used.
- What did you say, Merlyn?
- I say it's never used.
- No? Then why is that fire alight?
- You're right.
Our friend's apparently expected very soon.
Deuced considerate of the fellow.
I like a good fire.
Here's something!
- What do you make of it?
- It's blood on silk.
We got silk from last night's wreck.
You see? He was here last night.
JEM: Foolish of you to overlook this, Joss.
- One might even say careless.
See that, Sir Humphrey?
There's been many others, too.
An unusual place. Behind the curtain.
- A signal?
- You've hit it.
- Open the door at the end of the passage.
- Certainly.
- Thank you.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Joss, who is it who comes here?
- Would you like to know?
I'll tell you. Santa Claus. Every Christmas.
Things'll be a lot easier, if you tell me.
You don't plan these wrecks.
- Who does?
- You'll find out, Mr Law Officer.
The wall's covered in plaster!
- I left the door open for him.
- Good.
What about the signal? Better light it up for him.
I'll do that.
What about the women? Better bring them up.
Right. I'll get them.
- Watch him.
- Fetch my toddy while you're about it.
Right.
SIR HUMPHREY: Still blowing?
- Hard as ever, sir.
- Take your orders, Merlyn.
Another wreck? Tonight?
Captain Murray
would like to have dined with me.
He dislikes the food on shipboard, you know?
He was particularly mortified
at having to sail past here at dinner time,
which means, let's see, er, Barnard's Head...
- Nine o'clock or thereabouts.
- Yes, sir.
- What are they carrying, sir?
- Among other things, gold.
You must make quite certain.
I need the money very particularly.
I hope the wind drops after.
- I'm an indifferent sailor.
- What?
I'm going to take a little holiday.
I advise you to do the same.
- Why? What's happened? Is...
- Nothing yet.
But the authorities sent Mr Trehearne
down into Cornwall.
You see, they suspect.
I shall come back when it's blown over.
Then it's the last one?
It's the last of this series.
I shall catch the Falmouth packet tonight
for St-Malo.
I shall call back on the way,
so have the gold and valuables ready for me.
They're extremely fond of such things in France.
What about Trehearne?
When will your men be here?
If this is what saving your life
has brought us all to, I wish...
You don't think I'm enjoying this?
(Raucous laughter)
- Is anything wrong?
SIR HUMPHREY: Oh, no.
Our friend made a very elementary joke.
We're ready.
I've locked the women in the bedroom.
Everything, in fact, except the man himself.
Your groom left just before us.
An hour and a quarter there and back.
Which means Captain Boyle should be here
within ten minutes.
There's only one way you might save your skin.
Name the man and tell the whole story.
I took the precaution of bringing this warrant
for the fellow's apprehension.
His name will have to be filled in later
when we know it.
Like to write it in for us, Joss?
You've taken all the risks so far,
you and Harry and Salvation and the rest.
And what have you got out of it?
The bare pickings.
Have you thought of that?
You've a chance to break free of him for good.
Turn king's evidence. Why don't you?
Do you think he'd hesitate in your shoes? No.
- A man like that would save his own skin first.
- You think so?
- He'd sacrifice anybody.
- You seem to have a very clear picture of him.
What sort of a fellow do you think he really is?
This man deliberately plans the wrecking
of ships and the cold-blooded slaughter
of any who survive the wreck.
He remains aloof,
content to hire the scum
to do his murderous work for him,
thinking there's no blood on his own hands,
but there is, blood on his soul...
(Downstairs door bangs open)
- The military!
Watch him. I'll go down and tell them to surround
the place and to lie low till we give the word.
- Oh, what a beauty.
- (Laughter)
Stay where you are.
You devil!
Sir Humphrey!
- Look out! Some of the gang are here!
- He's got somebody with him.
- See nobody gets outside.
- Sir Humphrey!
There's no other way.
HARRY: Are you up there, Joss?
Joss?
(Harry whistles)
Squire Pengallan?
That's right. Your respected justice of the peace
brought here by your pal Mr Trehearne.
- Who forgot to tell you he's a law officer.
- What's that?
What do you think?
They came here to hang us over the wreck.
We'll make a real job of it this time. Come on.
Hold on.
- We've got to go careful.
- What's the matter?
We don't want our justice of the peace
found here dead. People might talk.
- He won't be found.
- But he might be missed.
Maybe they knew he was coming here.
- We've got to finish him.
- Surely,
but that takes a little thinking over
and there's no time for that now.
We're doing another wreck.
- Tonight?
- Nine o'clock.
We'll fix them when we come back.
Get a couple of ropes there.
JOSS: Chairs.
No, I'll do him. It'll be a pleasure.
Do you think I came here just for you?
I told you, there's somebody behind Joss.
If you wait here long enough, you'll see him.
He's coming here tonight.
You shut your gab. Playing for time, are you?
You'd like to see us miss that wreck we're doing
tonight. We wouldn't miss it for worlds.
Joss, finished trussing His Worship?
Let's make 'em nice and snug.
And while we're away, we've got to think
of a nice little accident for you.
Now, what would Your Worship fancy?
A choice coach over the cliffs?
Or perhaps you'd sooner be caught by the tide
with our friend Jem here
on a nice, comfortable, cosy part of the beach.
That's it. In death they shall not be divided.
I warn you, all of you, if you lay a finger
on either of us, you'll pay for it.
You'll end swinging in the wind at
Execution Dock with tar to keep the weather out.
- It's time we went.
- Well, who's going to stay with them?
What about Salvation?
He can talk to Mr Trehearne about eternity.
SALVATION: Him? Not me.
We'll need all hands on shore. Patience'll watch
'em. The women are locked in the bedroom.
I'm sorry to see you here, Willie Penhale.
I told you when you were up before me
for poaching you were among evil companions.
You should have listened to me, my boy.
It looks as though your wish is going to come
true. You might just as well have left me.
- What's she doing here?
- She came here to warn us.
- She started the whole thing. I don't see why...
- I'll look after her.
I've got a nice job for you, Patience.
Take this and watch the two gentlemen.
HARRY: You can't leave a woman in charge.
- I'll need you lot down at the beach.
They're tied. This is all the better for a finger
that's nervous, like, on the trigger.
I shouldn't move, bearing that in mind. You
wouldn't like your suit spoiled with a bullet hole.
You'll have no call to use it, most likely.
Come on. Look lively now!
- Patience, you can't leave them like...
- You're coming with us.
Take your hands off her.
You can't take her to the wreck.
Of course not. I'm going to leave her behind
to cut you loose for the second time in 24 hours.
Come on now.
Merlyn!
You'll answer to me for her safety.
Yes, Your Worship.
(Door is bolted)
- What's happened to the military?
- Something must have delayed them.
- If they'd come, we could save the wreck.
- We don't know where it's going to be.
- Our man came here, but he left before us.
- How do you mean?
Or Joss wouldn't have known about the wreck.
I warn you, Mrs Merlyn, if Captain Boyle
finds you like that, nothing will save you.
This is very annoying.
I told Chadwick I'd be back for dinner.
Mrs Merlyn,
I wonder if that pistol is loaded.
You're inexperienced in these things.
Would you like me to look?
- That'll never work.
- Very well, Mrs Merlyn.
Let's see if it's properly primed.
You're not fully conversant with the facts.
I know your husband better than you do.
He would no more have loaded that pistol
than he would have left me helpless,
which would have been quite absurd.
As I thought.
Now, Mrs Merlyn.
I've always admired
your devotion to your husband.
The woman shall cleave to the man,
even if the man is our friend Joss.
Admirable. Now, if this officer should escape...
...your husband will pay for it with his life,
so I needn't stress the importance
of the task I'm giving you.
There.
Watch him. Closely.
If there's the slightest chance of him getting free,
don't hesitate to shoot him.
Just get firm pressure on the trigger.
On the trigger.
And all will be well.
No.
JEM: You've forgotten one thing.
Captain Boyle.
There's still the military to reckon with.
There is no Captain Boyle.
In consequence, there'll be no military.
(Door slams shut)
Mrs Merlyn, you've got to let me go.
- Quick!
- Please. Don't move.
JOSS: Whoa! Take her round. Take her round.
Whoa!
Up to the beacon with you. Quick!
- Can't I join in the wreck?
- When you're grown to a man's size, maybe.
- I never see anything.
- Off with you!
(Harry whistles)
Would you like me to bring you back a nice ring?
Not including the finger, if you follow me.
Come down out of there!
Hold on to her, Catchpole.
Mrs Merlyn, where is the wreck going to be?
I don't know.
You can't let it happen. You must set me free.
Innocent men and women are going to die.
You'll be responsible.
You love your husband, I know that.
And I know it's my duty to take him if I can.
But the men on that ship have wives, too.
Think of yourself if Joss was on board.
That ship sailing down
from Falmouth in the gale.
Somewhere on the shore, a beacon is going out.
Can you see the rest?
The ship striking. Men spread out like flies,
clinging to the rigging, screaming at the surf.
And after the wreck, the wolves.
That's why you must let me go.
Tell me where that wreck is.
I can't. I can't. I don't know, I tell you.
I've never known.
Mrs Merlyn!
Let me go now and I'll find out where it is.
Hurry! There's hardly time.
I can't. What will happen to Joss?
You must make a choice. The lives of those men
and of other men in the future or Joss?
After all, Joss is only one man.
Yes, but he's my man.
Mrs Merlyn, supposing I allow your husband...
Hey!
- Whoa-up!
- Where's the nearest military garrison?
- Bodmin. Why?
- I want your coach.
Give me those reins in the name of the law.
Here's my warrant.
There she is! Look!
HELMSMAN: A light! Barnard's Head!
MURRAY: Hard a'port.
(Angry cries from gang)
She's the one that did it.
Women are no good here, bring you bad luck.
All right, Joss. You leave her to us.
We'll manage very nicely. Thank you.
DANDY: I'm sure you'll agree, Harry.
This calls for my attention.
This is where I come into my own.
Let her go! Get into that cart quick.
Keep back there.
- You can't take her.
- She's robbed us of our best cargo ever.
- Fetch her down.
MARY: Robbed you? Thank heaven!
Robbed of your chance to stuff your pockets
by murdering innocent devils you've never seen.
I'm glad. I don't care what happens.
- I'm glad!
- Shut your mouth, you little fool!
I don't know how long my business will take me.
- I may be away for some weeks.
- Very good, sir.
- Sir Humphrey!
- What is it, Sam?
I couldn't deliver this note.
The regiment left Truro three weeks ago.
- Nobody's heard of any Captain Boyle.
- Extraordinary.
- Shall I try Bodmin?
- No, no, it's of no importance.
That'll be all, Chadwick.
I can't give you my address in France.
- Sir!
- What?
Well, er, Chadwick?
You'll pardon the liberty.
You're not ill?
III, Chadwick?
III?
I've never felt better in my life.
Come here.
The fact is I'm, er...
growing younger.
Come here.
So much younger I'm taking
a beautiful young girl with me on my travels.
Yes, sir. Is there anything more?
Yes, you fool!
Don't stand there with that look in your eyes!
- Sam!
- Sir?
Keep the mare and bay
in good condition, won't you?
And, er, come here.
Watch Chadwick.
His mind's going.
Hm.
SIR HUMPHREY: Drive on, will you!
Mr Chadwick.
He's, erm...
I've seen that coming along for years.
Aunt Patience! Aunt Patience!
Mary! Joss! What's happened?
Joss is hurt.
Careful, Joss. Joss.
Mary!
(Joss coughs)
Mary. Mary, what happened?
I stopped the wreck. The men came for me
and Joss saved me and they shot him.
(Coughs)
Uhh!
Joss, Joss.
Oh, Patience.
Patience, my dear.
You're all right, Joss. I'm taking care of you.
You're a good girl, Patience.
I'm sorry.
Where's Jem? Aunt Patience, he's not?
I set him free.
He went to find the wreck.
Mary, he promised me he'd let Joss escape.
You know what that means. We can leave here.
We can leave here together, Joss and I.
You must help me, Mary.
We must go quickly while we can.
Mary, we'll begin again.
Think of it. To be able to live without fear
- among different people who don't know us.
- Yes, Aunt Patience.
It'll be like those first days in Bodmin.
Joss was different then.
He's strong.
He'll soon get better, won't he?
- (Coughs)
- Of course.
When he's recovered a little, we must move him.
We can't wait. Joss mustn't be here when...
when he comes back.
Who?
Oh, Mary, I haven't told you.
I didn't know myself until tonight, but I've always
known Joss wasn't his own master.
There's someone else who planned the wrecks
and had Joss in his power.
Tonight I found out who. Mary, it's...
(Gunshot)
Aunt Patience! Aunt Patience!
Life without Patience?
Get me a drink.
Yes, Joss, yes.
A good, clean shot, wasn't it?
I'm sorry.
Poor creature. She has suffered so much.
But I was forced to do it, you see.
She was going to tell you about me.
I didn't like that.
I wanted to tell you myself.
So, you stopped the wreck?
Pity. I was counting on it.
You're a very brave young lady,
but you've made my position very difficult.
- Let me go! Let me go!
- Please don't scream like that.
I shall have to put this handkerchief
in your mouth. You must tell me if that hurts.
Of course, you can't. How silly of me.
Put your hands down. Put your hands down.
Or I shall have to tie them up, too.
Right.
This will prevent the cord
from cutting your wrists.
You see, you're quite alone now.
You have no-one else in the world.
Except myself.
So I'm going to take care of you.
Er... in fact, we're going away together.
We should be going now.
Trehearne may come back.
You'd better put this on.
It's wise to wrap up well,
while this cold wind is blowing.
I'm always telling people
they can't be too careful.
But they think they know better.
And you wouldn't want people
to see you like that, would you?
There.
I'm er... glad you're quiet now.
Now, come along.
My coach is not far away.
(Mary sobs)
But we must hurry.
We must hurry.
HARRY: Sir Humphrey!
And the girl's with him.
- But Joss, what about Joss?
- Come on!
DANDY: Trehearne's gone, too.
ALL: Joss! Joss!
SALVATION: Harry, here! Quick!
Dead. Both of them.
You shouldn't have done that to Joss, Harry.
If you ask me, it's er... time we moved on.
What are you all standing there for? Get out!
Don't keep together. Scatter.
Soldiers!
Now, where's that girl?
- That's the question.
- Come on now, where is she? Tell me.
Take it calm now, take it calm.
You're going to be disappointed, Mr Trehearne.
She's gone and found herself
another gentleman.
I just seen her sneaking off alone
with His Worship.
The squire.
We've got to find them, Captain.
Sergeant, I want six men
to ride with Mr Trehearne and myself.
I don't like it. I don't like it at all.
It was breaking that...
that bit of looking glass that did it.
I told you. Seven years' bad luck.
No, Dandy, not more than seven days.
Not counting eternity.
What'll they do? What'll happen to us?
Lt'll be a proper public execution
with the women watching. I'll make 'em sit up.
I'm ready. Ready.
- That won't do, will it?
- Better tie him up.
Why are you doing that?
Why can't I be chained? Stop.
Stop. I want to be chained like the others.
Listen to me.
I've got a right to be. I'm the same as them.
I've done what they've done, haven't I?
I want to hang with them.
You'll hang me.
I don't want to hang.
I don't want to die. Not yet.
I'm only a boy. I'm only 1 7!
You won't let them, will you?
I only did what I was told.
I never killed anybody.
I never even went near the wrecks.
So you can't hang me.
You mustn't. You daren't!
Because I don't want to die.
(Sobs) I don't want to die.
(Harry whistles)
There's my house. Do you see?
Across the bay.
The Pengallans have been there a long time.
I may never see it again.
Because, you see,
we may never be able to come back.
We may be going a long way, you know.
Nearer the sun, of course.
Italy perhaps. The Isles of Greece.
You're thinking that'll cost money,
but there, I have enough.
One must have enough.
I always knew that to live like a gentleman,
spaciously and with elegance,
one must have money.
And a few beautiful possessions, of course,
like you, my dear.
- Where's Sir Humphrey?
- Sir Humphrey has gone away on business.
- Where?
- Answer, man, answer!
Sir Humphrey is taking
the Falmouth night packet to St-Malo.
I say, I say, what's this? Oh, it's you.
Good heavens! My suit!
These gentlemen
are enquiring for Sir Humphrey, sir.
Sir Humphrey is the head of a band of wreckers
who are under arrest at Jamaica Inn.
(Clock chimes)
HAWKER: Sweet China oranges.
Sweet China.
I've put your luggage below, sir.
Sir Humphrey Pengallan. The large stateroom.
Are you the steward?
Get me a bottle of brandy.
Very good, sir. This way, sir. Follow me.
What a miserable hole.
Is this the best they've got?
Old traveller, though.
I'll make you comfortable.
I never really cared for wrecking.
After all, not my kind of thing,
hobnobbing with cut-throats.
It had to be done.
Half my friends living like paupers.
But I'm living like a prince.
Drowned hundreds of sailors to do it.
But like a prince.
And I'll make a princess out of you.
I believe you're sorry,
because you're not marrying some oaf,
who'd father on you a dozen
snivelling, dirty-nosed brats.
Any man of sensibility
would rather see you dead first.
Gangplank away!
(Crowd shout goodbyes)
In Paris you'll have your woman to attend to you.
I'll see to your new clothes myself.
Yes, I'll dress you, my dear.
And we'll put silk
next to that smooth skin of yours, hmm?
Pale green silk, I think, what?
(Mary sobs)
(Sir Humphrey laughs)
Pah! Stop crying!
Stop it, you little fool!
Be beautiful! Hard as nails if you like,
but you must be beautiful.
Well, you have to be hard now.
The age of chivalry has gone.
(Horses approaching)
CAPTAIN JOHNSON:
That's it. Bring her back to the quayside!
SIR HUMPHREY:
Troopers. They may be coming for you.
Of course, you can't go with them.
You shouldn't have done that, my child.
Lots of riffraff about.
Things might be most unpleasant.
(Mary screams)
Captain Johnson!
I'm here!
Sir Humphrey Pengallan!
Give yourself up, I beg you, Sir Humphrey,
and let her go!
Pray, keep your distance.
Careful. Wing him if possible.
Take care!
Lean away from him as far as you can!
No, don't shoot. He can't help himself!
He doesn't know what he's doing!
He's mad, I tell you! Mad!
It's safer here.
SAILOR: Port bow line ashore there!
It must be now.
Please be still.
Jem, don't harm him!
It's not his fault. He can't help himself.
JEM: Come down!
Come down from the rigging
and give yourself up!
Come down!
Come down, Sir Humphrey!
Come down, sir. Come down!
Good heavens,
what's the squire doing up there?
JEM: Come down, Sir Humphrey,
and give yourself up!
You'll not be harmed, I promise you!
Come down, sir!
I shall be down to you before you're up to me,
Mr Trehearne.
If you'll be kind enough to give me room.
OFFICER: Bring that man down!
- All right, sir.
SIR HUMPHREY: What are you all waiting for?
A spectacle?
You shall have it.
And tell your children how the great age ended!
Make way for Pengallan!
(Screaming)
(Thud)
SIR HUMPHREY'S VOICE: Chadwick!
(Fainter) Chadwick!